<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A message brought to the Parliament, concerning the treaty, between the King and the commissioners brought by Sir Peter Killeygrew on Tuesday 17 Octob. 1648. With the commissioners propositions, and His Majesties answer, Newport the 12 of October. 1648.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A89103</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99864769</idno>
  <idno type="VID">162338</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240902373</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing M1898</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E468_20</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R205369</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99864769</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99864769e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A89103)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 162338)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 75:E468[20])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A message brought to the Parliament, concerning the treaty, between the King and the commissioners brought by Sir Peter Killeygrew on Tuesday 17 Octob. 1648. With the commissioners propositions, and His Majesties answer, Newport the 12 of October. 1648.</title>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 3 [i.e. 5], [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for R. Smithurst, neer Pye-corner,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Page numbers 4 and 5 misnumbered 6 and 3, respectively.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "8ber [i.e. October] ye 19th".</note>
                  <note>Imprint place from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Monarchy --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:162338:1"/>
            <p> A MESSAGE Brought to the <hi>Parliament, concerning the TREATY,</hi> Between the <hi>KING and the COMMISSIONERS</hi> Brought by Sir <hi>Peter Killeygrew</hi> on Tuesday 17 Octob. 1648.</p>
            <p>With the Commissioners Propositions, and His Majesties Answer, <hi>Newport</hi> the 12 of <hi>October,</hi> 1648.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
               <head>C R</head>
               <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
            </figure>
            <p>Printed for <hi>R. Smithurst,</hi> neer Pye-corner 1648,</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:162338:2"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:162338:2"/>
            <head>A Message brought to the Parliament, concerning the Treaty between the <hi>King</hi> and the <hi>Commissioners.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>May it please your Majesty,</opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>E do pray your Majesties assent for the passing of such Act or Acts for raising of monies for the payment and satisfying of the publick debts and damages of the Kingdome, and other publick uses as shall hereafter be agreed on by both Houses of Parliament, and that if the King doe not give his assent thereunto, then, it being done by both Houses of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, the same shall bee as vallid to all in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:162338:3"/> and purposes as if the Royall assent had been given thereunto.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Newport <date>13 October. 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="response">
            <opener>
               <signed>CHARLES R.</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>HIS Majesty doth give His con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent to the passing of their Propo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sition of the 12 of <hi>Octob.</hi> as is desired. The time for bringing in Accounts being limiting for two years.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Newport</hi>
                  <date>13 <hi>Oct.</hi> 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="petition">
            <opener>May it please your Majesty,</opener>
            <p>VVE do pray your Majesties assent, that by Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, all Peeres made since the day that <hi>Edward</hi> Lord <hi>Littleton,</hi> then Lord Keeper of the Great Seale dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>serted the Parliament, and that the said
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:162338:3"/> Great Seale was surreptitiously con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyed away from the Parliament be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the 21 of <hi>May</hi> 1642. And who shal be hereafter made, shal not sit or Vote in the Parliament of <hi>England</hi> without consent of both Houses of Parliament And that all Honors and Tittles con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred on any, without consent of both Houses of Parliament since the 21th day of May 1642) being the day that both Houses declared, <hi>That the King, seduced by evill Counsell, intend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to raise War against the Parliament)</hi> be declared null and void.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Newport</hi>
                  <date>14 <hi>Octob.</hi> 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="response">
            <opener>
               <signed>CHARLES R.</signed>
            </opener>
            <p>HIs Majesty doth give His consent to the passing of your Proposition of the 13th of October.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Newport <date>14 Octob. 1648.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="list">
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:162338:4"/>
            <head>A List of the names of persons presented to His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty to be excepted out of Mercy.</head>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>Prince</hi> Rupert</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Prince</hi> Maurice</item>
               <item>James <hi>Earle of</hi> Darby,</item>
               <item>John <hi>Earle of</hi> Bristoll</item>
               <item>William <hi>Earle of</hi> Newcastle</item>
               <item>Francis <hi>Lord</hi> Cottington,</item>
               <item>George <hi>Lord</hi> Digby,</item>
               <item>Matthew Wren <hi>Bishop of</hi> Ely</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Robert Heath <hi>Knight,</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Doctor</hi> Brambal <hi>Bishop of</hi> Derry</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> William Widdrington,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Colonell</hi> George Goring,</item>
               <item>Henry Jermin <hi>Esquire,</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Ralph Hopton,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Francis Doddington,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr.</hi> Endimon Porter,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> George Radcliffe,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Marmaduke Langdale</item>
               <item>Henry Vaughan <hi>Esquire, now called Sir</hi> Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Vaughan.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Francis Windibanke,</item>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:162338:4"/>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Richard Greenvill,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr.</hi> Edward Hide, <hi>now called Sir</hi> Edward Hide.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> John Marley,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Nicholas Cole,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Thomas Riddell <hi>Juniour,</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> John Culpepper,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr.</hi> Richard Lloyd, <hi>now called Sir</hi> Richard Lloyd.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr.</hi> David Jenkins</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> George Strode,</item>
               <item>George Carteret, <hi>Esquire, now called Sir</hi> George Carteret,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Charles Dallison <hi>Knight,</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Richard Lane <hi>Esquire, now called Sir</hi> Richard Lane,</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Edward Nicholas.</item>
               <item>John Ashburnham, <hi>Esquire,</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Sir</hi> Edward Harbert <hi>Knight, His Majesties Atturney Generall.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>